<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Purpose on The Approximate Mind</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/purpose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Purpose on The Approximate Mind</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/purpose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Approximate Mind, Part 19: The New Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-shared-world/the-new-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-shared-world/the-new-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question everyone asks is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What jobs will AI take?&amp;rdquo; assumes a fixed pie of work that AI and humans divide between them. It treats labor as a zero-sum competition where every AI capability is a human loss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Approximate Mind, Part 20: My Childhood AI Buddy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-shared-world/my-childhood-ai-buddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-shared-world/my-childhood-ai-buddy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happens to identity when everything that used to define us can&#xA;be outsourced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking about children growing up right now&amp;mdash;kids who will&#xA;be teenagers when AI has fully arrived, adults when its implications&#xA;have settled into ordinary life. What will they learn? What will they&#xA;strive for? What will they remember about growing up?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Approximate Mind, Part 52: The Empty Ledger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-structures-we-live-in/the-empty-ledger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-structures-we-live-in/the-empty-ledger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;James graduated eighteen months ago with a degree in communications and a plan that felt, at the time, reasonable. He would find an entry-level position at a marketing firm or a nonprofit or a media company. He would do the unglamorous work that every career begins with: writing copy, assembling reports, summarizing research, drafting press releases that no one would read carefully. He would learn by doing. He would prove himself through effort. Over five or ten years, this effort would accumulate into something that people call a career, which is really just a ledger of contributions that establishes you as a person who produces value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
