<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Synthesis on The Approximate Mind</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/synthesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Synthesis on The Approximate Mind</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/synthesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Approximate Mind, Part 10: What We&#39;ve Learned and What Remains Unknown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-approximation/what-remains-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-approximation/what-remains-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is where I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to wrap everything up. Ten articles exploring how AI approaches understanding, what it can approximate, what remains beyond reach. Time for the synthesis, the grand conclusion, the neat ending.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Approximate Mind, Part 55: What Remains</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-structures-we-live-in/what-remains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-structures-we-live-in/what-remains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gather the threads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A confluence of AI systems converges on Margaret&amp;rsquo;s Tuesday morning, shaping her groceries, her health monitoring, her news, her social connections, each system optimizing its domain without coordinating with the others, the cumulative effect unplanned and ungoverned (Part 49). The economic variety that sustained Dot&amp;rsquo;s honey stand on Route 9 is collapsing as recommendation algorithms route customers toward optimized defaults, killing diversity through mathematics rather than predation (Part 50). The market that was supposed to serve Margaret&amp;rsquo;s desires is now producing them, her preferences shaped by the systems that claim to satisfy them, curation experienced as autonomy (Part 51). James sits at his desk at eleven-fifteen on a Tuesday with his tasks completed and his purpose unfilled, employed but unnecessary, his ledger of contribution empty not because he does not work but because the work no longer needs him (Part 52). Three mechanisms lock this structure in place: the efficiency trap that dismantles the infrastructure for un-optimized alternatives, the concentration spiral that consolidates markets through mathematical inevitability, and the fiscal fracture that breaks the budget assumptions underlying public programs (Part 53). Elena lies awake at 1:40 a.m. because her body correctly perceives an ambient, unresolvable threat, and the correct response, sustained past its design parameters, is destroying her health and the health of a generation (Part 54).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
